

Ali Behzadian Nejad

Technical Manager, Software Developer, Tech Blogger and Writer

About Me

Technical manager, Project Manager, Consultant and software developer. I write about my experiences in software development and startups in Smartlab blog. I've translated "Getting Real" and "Zero to One" books into Persian.

Skills

Managing Software Projects

Mobile Development (Especially Android)

C# and .Net Development

Java EE Development

Business Development

Experience

Asiacom Investment Company

Tehran, Iran

January 2016 – January 2017

CTO

Responsible for Development of Nationwide Project called "Portal Taavon"

Gaj International Publications

Tehran, Iran

October 2015 – September 2016

Project Manager

Lead Developer and Project
Manager in Software
Development Department.
Responsible for Gaj Android Apps
and its website.

Parmis IT Institute

Mashhad, Iran

January 2011 - October 2015

Android Instructor

Responsible for designing Basic and Advanced Android Development Courses and teaching students.

Farayan IT

Mashhad, Iran

August 2011 - October 2015

Lead Developer

Developing Android applications. One of them was bestselling app in CafeBazaar market.

Rayan Pardaz Kavosh

Tehran, Iran

January 2008 – October 2009

Java EE Developer

Working on Bank Tejarat ERP system

Miaad Andisheh Saz

Tehran, Iran

April 2007 – January 2008

Lead Java Developer

Working on Tehran Municipality's GIS Project And Some Failed Startups and Companies that I am proud of!

Education

B.S in Computer Science, Amirkabir University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

Publications

Persian Translation of "Zero to One" Book, Hoormazd publiations (Soon)

Persian Translation of "Getting Real" Book, Hoormazd publication (Soon)

A. Behzadian Nejad and A. S. Saffarian, "Recovery-Oriented Sofware Systems". First international student ICT conference, Shiraz University, 2004.

A. Behzadian Nejad and A. S. Saffarian, "Reliability in Multi-Agent Systems". First international student ICT conference, Shiraz University, 2004.

Membership

Mathematics and Computer Scientific Association, 2002, 2003 and 2004, Amirkabir University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

Awards

Member of StackOverFlow since 2012 with 4 gold, 32 silver, 63 bronze badges and 3200 reputation, top 11% users overall and top 5% android users.

Attending RoboCupResue Simulation competions in 2003 as supervisor of Rayan Team.

Contact

Location: Tehran, Iran

Phone: +98 935 475 7626

Email: ali.behzadian@gmail.com

Website: ali.behzadian.info

GitHub: alibehzadian